[Music]
well my outlook for for the insurance
industry in Vietnam is very very
positive for many reasons I guess the
first would be the Vietnam economy GDP
growth rates have been growing at a
significant pace as an example in in
2017 GDP growth rates were six point
eight one percent in 2018 they were over
seven percent
highest in ten years and from all
projections that GDP growth is going to
continue number two
the government regulators are doing a
really good job at understanding the
consumer needs as well as the insurance
company needs and they're coming up with
regulation changes that enhance the
consumers opportunities to ground
insurance products and their experience
as well as helping insurance companies
to deliver those products to consumers
with things like a signature etc number
three the Vietnam population is very
very focused on on health that's
becoming one of their priorities which
bodes well for the insurance industry
because of our health related products
insurance protection products is really
helping consumers release some of that
angst that they have around their own
health and I think number four is is
insurance companies are really
recognizing that they need to become
better and looking after the consumer so
in other words increasing their
touchpoints with consumers delivering
better value to the consumer and with
that increased touchpoints increases the
opportunities for the insurance industry
in vietnam so I think those are four
real good reasons why I believe that the
the opportunity in the vietnam
marketplace for insurance companies is
is very very very good and will continue
to expand
I kind of look funny because every
challenge I see also see an opportunity
because of many factors and one being is
the insurance penetration rates here in
in Vietnam are are very low they're the
lowest in the ASEAN countries at 8% of
the population only insurance that's a
huge opportunity and when you see that
along with some of the other things I've
talked about
there's many insurance companies
international that really want to be
playing in this market and with the
large third largest population in the
ASEAN countries with over 90 million
people insurance companies want to be
here so that creates in some ways an
obstacle because it drives the
competition for staff distribution
everything else but the reality is it's
also an opportunity because this is a
big market it's got low penetration
rates better the competition forces
insurance companies to deliver better to
consumers and ultimately that obstacle
becomes an opportunity for the consumer
I also see and we've done a lot of work
around this but the the Vietnam
population is becoming very technology
savvy they're very much on the Internet
have a high penetration of smartphones
the average person is on the internet
for hours a day so it's very high which
means that the average Vietnam citizen
is becoming more educated more engaged
and demanding more of the matter whether
it's a consumer product insurance
product whatever so it's forcing
insurance companies to become better so
that's an obstacle but for companies
that recognize that obstacle and deliver
on that it's an opportunity so what's an
obstacle really can be an opportunity
[Music]
well our focus in in Manulife Vietnam is
to be the most digital customer centric
organization in Vietnam we are very
focused on enhancing our digital
transformation and delivering more
digital technology to our distribution
forces as well as the consumers so I
believe yes Vietnam is similar to the
rest of the world and and and the
consumers demanding more they're
demanding when they want to talk to an
insurance company how they want to talk
to an insurance company is that in
person is it through digital it's more
of an omni-channel approach and we're
very very focused on doing that in our
company and over the last number of
years we've invested significantly in
that digital transformation journey with
many many different things I think
there's there's that there's a number of
things number one I think that the the
that real drive on the digital
transformation is is a very important
things and a lot of companies are
talking about it
we're actually delivering on this and
we're driving this very very hard even
within our own company Vietnam is being
recognized as one of the leaders within
the Manulife world across across the
globe I also think that one of the
things that is a clear differentiator
for us is our professional distribution
force we are recognized by consumers and
by the industry is having the most
professional distribution force in the
industry and that's for a lot of reasons
but one of the key ones is that we
invest very heavily
first of all hiring the right type of
person number two developing them on an
ongoing basis basis throughout their
career because ultimately we want to
deliver the best value to our customer
and customers are telling us that they
want professional people working with
them I also think that what it is a real
clear differentiator is is is our people
we were recognized as the the best
insurance company to work for in the
insurance industry and I think that's
for a lot of reasons but one is is that
we really truly
are committed around our own staff when
staff are engaged they get engaged with
the customer so ultimately by doing the
right thing for your own people
it ultimately impacts the customer on a
very very significant basis and I also
want to ensure that how we measure that
is through very high employee engagement
scores when you have very high employee
engagement scores and you're in the top
quartile of global companies that tells
you that you're doing a good job and
that's exactly where we are so so I
think ultimately what differentiates us
is our people well we've got a number of
priorities but I but I believe that we
want to continue on the digital
transformation journey we want to ensure
that our customers see us as a customer
driven company that they are number one
with us we need to do that we need to
continue to invest and develop in our
distribution because there's a lot of
times that the first person that engages
with a consumer and we have to continue
to engage and invest in our people our
staff to ensure that they are very very
strong confident and excited about what
we're doing as a company to our
customers and improving and continuing
to even though we're very good on
employee engagement scores continue to
drive that so really revolves around the
consumer and being recognized as
exceptional and customer service and
really looking after our distribution
and our staff to ensure that they are
developed and ultimately look after the
customer
[Music]
Vietnam will be very similar to the rest
of the world and I think that consumers
you know there's different buckets of
consumers you know some want to deal
with a company through digital means and
that's how they want to do it could be
Millennials that feel very confident and
comfortable working and all they want to
do is have access to a company through a
digital channel very large percentage
people also want to deal with face to
face because although they they get a
lot of information off the internet it
can be very confusing you know what's
the right thing to do I'm not sure and
it can be very confusing I think every
one of us experience that when we're on
the internet looking for different
products or different sources of
information for ourselves so
distribution will always need to have
very strong advisory forces that that
help the consumer and develop a rich
relationship with them and help them on
their life journey because people
throughout life have changes and with
those changes come the need to sit down
and talk to the professional person that
understands their situation and is able
to help guide them and work with them to
ensure that they actually have what they
need to ensure that they and their
families are okay as insurance companies
become smarter start listening to the
customer better I believe that all the
different areas within the omni-channel
approach really will work
[Music]